[Speaker 1] All right, so now I'm going to show you how to turn all of these patterns you've just come up with from outliers into video ideas and a strategy. Most important thing to mention here, though, is that you will fail if you make videos that are not based on these patterns. Like I said in the last video, don't just come up with ideas and be like, I'm going to try that. It is not going to work. But also keep this in mind. So if you are a existing channel, you've got an existing following, if you do this and then you start making videos that are like wildly different from what your viewers expect from you, you're going to get less views. So keep that in mind, too. If we're experienced, we want to be doing this. So I'm going to use this image again. All the colored ones are me just repeating what works. The ones in between, so this one and this one, were crap for views and sales. They just didn't work, right? All of these other ones, they've got varying views, but they either grew the business a ton or got a ton of views. So as far as I'm concerned, they're all outliers. It's literally me just repeating what worked. So what I try and do. Is every three or four videos, I try the new thing, knowing it's probably not going to work, but then I just keep playing it safe, repeating what works over and over again. So don't necessarily feel like you need to reinvent the wheel. Every video you make, you don't. All right. So I'm going to show you how to come up with a title. So the first thing we do is we go to our patent bank. And what you're going to have is you're going to have your channels data. You're going to have people from your niches, adjacent niches. All you need to do is come up with one title from this data. So. So I'm going to say, look, I'm going to try something slightly different. But this title here, I really like drumming mistakes that kill your progress. I did them all. Nine hundred thousand views. It's also in line with the things that we know our viewers like. Right. So the viewers based on our own channel, who to meet, she's kind of love mistakes. So I feel pretty safe and another mistakes video being worth a shot. And I think this is kind of an interesting title. So I'm going to say, all right, let's pick this. Then I'm going to adjust it. So. So I'm going to turn it to just drawing mistakes that kill your hand speed that I did them all. I'm not sure I might put that in. I don't know yet if that's actually helpful. I feel like this is good because we know that in Dimitri's channel, hand speed was the thing they cared about. Right. So they love fast. They loved speed. So they don't want to lose that. So I feel pretty confident saying mistakes that kill the house speed. It's a format viewers like, which is a mistakes video listicle. And it's about the thing they really care about. So this feels like a good video. It is. For me. And then what we're going to do is just going to run it through the title checklist. So the title checklist is basically going to make sure it's not too long. It's not confusing. They use power words. And as you can see, it takes off pretty much everything on that list. So happy days. Then I'm going to do is I'm going to ask guardrails for feedback. Now, I don't have Dimitri's guardrails up here, but all you would do is you would put this in and say, is this a good idea? .
[Speaker 1] So awesome. So I've got a little egg embrace up here and I'm going to move this first thing. And I'm just going to be showing myself a brought a little Virgin Access Play. So listen,
[Speaker 1] we're going to play a third one in a row. What's the time certain here for him that seems just about, like 4 omuj bottle com not doing it's my best guess because he's going to take it. NBD Let's pull that. Right. anything that we might have missed. And then we're gonna use a human, a real life human for feedback too, so long as you have that package. And all that means is you go to Discord, go to packaging feedback, new post, put your title in here, can I get feedback on this title? But just keep in mind, if you're an experienced channel and you already have outliers, then we're just gonna look at your channel to make sure they're in line with your channel first. That's why it's important you put your URL in your description here so that we can actually click on it. I haven't done it, naughty Ed. So that's it, the first step is just a title for a video. And then what we do is we come up with three thumbnails for each title. Now, you're gonna be going, what the, three? And you're gonna hate me. But let me show you why this is one of the biggest time -saving things you're ever gonna do on YouTube and one of the most important, because YouTube now gives us the split tester. So if I go over to my YouTube studio,
[Speaker 1] every video I make, we can load three thumbnails in. And what that means is we can learn three times faster. So let's say we put out one video and a yellow video is a lesson learned. This column on the left, they listened to what I told them to do and they put in three thumbnails. And it was very clear that one thumbnail style won by a mile. So we go, ah, we'll take that lesson into our next video. This person ignored me and went, now I'm just gonna do one thumbnail per video. And it meant they had to post three videos until they learned that same lesson. Now you might be thinking, I'm still gonna do it, but well, after nine weeks, this is how many lessons we can learn my way. And then this is how much time you waste if you do it the other way. But even more terrifying, if you ignored me for three years, which many of you will, but you're gonna do it again,
[Speaker 1] you're gonna do it again, Posting one video a week, we could learn 52 lessons over the course of the year, making three thumbnails. Making one, it will take us three years to learn the same amount of lessons. You will waste two years if you ignore me. So look, it's up to you. You probably have a brain and you probably have quite an intelligent brain seeing as you could afford this program.
[Speaker 1] Take this seriously. But look, it doesn't have to be that much work. Now to start, if you're new and small, it's gonna hurt this, like making three thumbnails is a lot, but the time savings are massive. So the way we do it is like this. We're gonna put three different strategies for each title. So remember there was like six or seven strategies I showed you. So let's say the title is this one, exactly how to create a million dollar YouTube strategy. The first strategy I always use is cognitive dissonance. So cognitive dissonance, if you remember, is basically telling people not to do something, something they thought they should be doing in its simplest form. We kind of challenge what they thought to be true. So people like to use SEO to grow their YouTube channels. I always tell them not to, so that would get their attention. Then I've tried a result based one. The result here is simply just putting a million dollar channel in the thumbnail and that's kind of it. And then this is a comparison one. Could still maybe class it as a result because it's got before and after and it's showing zero to a million, that's it. So the process is this. We research patterns, we make a title, we make three thumbnails for it, and then YouTube will give you some data. Now I'm not gonna go into details of how this works right now. We'll do it later in the measurement and launching module. And then we set the winner. And then if we learn a lesson, we can then take that lesson into the next video and grow. So what you're gonna do for creating a thumbnail is this. So the first things first is don't just go and make like a really polished thumbnail. All I would do is this. So we've got this title that we're gonna take, drawing mistakes that kill your hand speed. Now we need to come up with some concepts. And we know that from the thumbnails that works already, just play this as text did really well. We know that curiosity thumbnails did well, results thumbnails and social hacking thumbnails did well. So I'm just gonna try a curiosity result and a social hack based on the data I found of what's doing well. And then we've got still this, stop this, do this. So I might just use some of this text again cause it's already worked. So Dimitri's channel is, if we look at his outliers, it's always drums being shown. We don't need to try and reinvent the wheel. Let's just keep it simple, right? I like this one, big drum here. Stop this, it's a mistakes one. So I'm probably gonna take this other guy's title, which we've adjusted and make it look more like a genuine Dimitri. So we might turn around and go, right, let's doodle the drum being played. And what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna imagine that there's a big drum here and there's some sticks here. And there's some hands here. Now drums are a lot harder to draw than just a person's face. And then we would have stopped this. Like, do you know what? I'm gonna put on two lines cause that's gonna fill the gap a bit better. What are we gonna do here? Hopefully you guys can see a thumbnail mistake. Got this horrid big line in the middle. So I'm gonna reduce that line. And then what we got here is, why is that all wonky? Anyway, a little arrow and some of these dots. Remember I showed you the dots, how they work. So I might turn around and go, right, we're gonna bring in some of Dimitri's dots. And it's gonna be very, very draft, but we don't need anything more than very draft. Like this doesn't need to be a masterpiece.
[Speaker 1] So that's one draft. And then I'd go, right, this is the curiosity. Stop what? Now I need a result one, because that was the other strategy we thought we'd try based on what had worked. So I'm gonna go to, I'm gonna look at Dimitri's own channel cause he's got lots of cool stuff on here. I don't think I need to go to the competition. And I'm gonna say, I like just play this. Oh no, do you know what people liked in his is they like speed. So I'm gonna do something like faster hands in one week. I might try something as simple as drum from the top down like this. So I'm gonna do another little doodle. It's gonna be another amazing work of art.
[Speaker 1] It's gonna be something as simple as like drum stick. All right, just pretend that there's a good sticks here.
[Speaker 1] Some hands coming in, holding the sticks. This looks weird. And then what I'm gonna have is play. I'm gonna make five X big. Remember text boxing, where we make the lines kind of as big. And then we're gonna go faster.
[Speaker 1] Look at this, what a work of art we have. All right. So I'm not gonna worry if things overlap right now, or there's like dodgy design mistakes, like having the text too close to the side. That's all we want. We've got the second one, rough design.
[Speaker 1] Okay, and then the next one I would have as like a social hack and just to save you some mucking around. This is what I made earlier. This is supposed to represent Dave Grohl.
[Speaker 1] So this is Dave Grohl playing the drums and it would be a good photo of him. And then we'd have stopped this with like an arrow pointing at him. So we'd probably go on Google and find an image of him playing the drums and then just have stopped doing this. And I came up with this art because we've got here, look, his outlier, Phil Collins, right? And maybe we could bring in some drum music and mistake, but this one here, I think I'm just gonna keep it simple. So then the next thing I want you to do is to go to this website, it's called thumbsup .tv. Put in the title and then whack in your image. And it's gonna show this YouTube looking thing. Then we're gonna screenshot it and we're gonna dump it onto a vision board. Now I use some software called Milanote. You really don't have to use that. You can access this if you don't want. Like I think I paid for it. I don't actually know. Got some good accounting skills there. And then we're gonna do that with all of them. So some others playing a drum there. And then we're gonna go to this one. Same thing. Stop this. Okay, I'm gonna wipe that in. So we've now got this little vision board where we got a rough idea of what's going on. And I like to put the outlier. These have been based on two. So I might screenshot one of the, outliers here. Just have this on the vision board too. So that you can see where all the pieces of the puzzle are come from. Then what you're gonna do is just line it up like this.
[Speaker 1] And just screenshot the whole thing. So then for those of you on the support package, they then just go back to the feedback, type in the title, new post. And then you're just gonna drop in that image. And you're gonna say, can I get some feedback? And then we're gonna post it. And you just wait for us guys to come in and give you feedback. Now, what we're gonna do is we know that these are doodles. Okay? So we're not gonna turn around and go, oh, this looks awful. We're just looking at this. Is the strategy good? Is it nice and simple? Is the copy interesting? Does it work with this sort of title? And it's also super helpful if you do put the outliers that made it up. Because what a lot of people do is they ignore everything I've taught them to do. Even though they've paid a lot of money to listen to me, tell them what to do. And they're like, they just come up with their own ideas. And me and the team know, we've been doing YouTube for years. So I can see when an idea is not based on an outlier cause I know millions of outliers.
[Speaker 1] So to save us from going, is this based on an outlier? Which is basically us saying, we think you've made this up, go back and do this properly. Put this here to stop us asking it now.
[Speaker 1] Or put these here so we can make sure you actually based on outlier. Cause sometimes people don't realize that they've misunderstood outliers. So it's helpful if you have this. Once you've been using the system a while and you've got used to the feedback, you can probably start to drop that out because you'll have stopped ignoring what I tell you to do.
[Speaker 1] And that's it. So we might give you a bit of feedback and say, look, drumming mistakes that kill your hand speed, play five times faster. That's positive. This title is negative. Maybe we should have a negative and a negative rather than a positive negative. So stop playing power diddles, something like that. But that will depend on the content. So once you've done this, you then go and make the designs. And then what I'd recommend doing is you can just drop these images into the thumbnail bot. Now I haven't got the thumbnail bot in front of me inside the YouTube coach, but it looks something like this or will look like this. You will put in a title of your video and then you'll just drop in the image. And it's gonna do a quick check to make sure you're not making any of the design mistakes people do like overcrowdedness. Now keep in mind, this is not perfect. It's just a very fast way of doing a design check. And then I'd recommend you come and you drop again. I know it's a pain in the butt, but you drop again your thumbnails into the feedback room like Stefan has done here amazingly. Now I used to get everyone to make nine thumbnails like this which is actually optimum because then we can look at different text examples and stuff. But so many people complained. I got it back to three. If you wanna do it nine like this, right? You basically have three different photos and then three different texts for each photo and we'll help pick the top three. But I cut it back to three because I listened to your guys' feedback. All right. So once you've done that, you've got a thumbnail and a title, that's your idea. And I'll teach you how to use the split tester later,
[Speaker 1] but that's it. And then you just repeat this. So really you wanna batch the ideation and come up with three to four thumbnails and titles at once for different videos. Because what that mean is you can drop it into our feedback. We can give you feedback on all of them in one go. It will be much quicker for you to produce them too. But before I move on, just wanna show you a problem that you're gonna come up against when you're doing this. So let's say we are researching this channel. So this is a channel called Theory of One that's growing really quick. This lady's great. And you can see she's got some videos down here with 200 ,000 views, 200 ,000 views. Like she's smashing it as a new channel. 20 ,000 views, 48 ,000 views. That one went off and did amazing things very fast.
[Speaker 1] So let's say she's in our niche or an adjacent nation. We're like, oh yeah, cool. I'm gonna take some of her patterns and ideate from this channel. So if we break down what her viewers want, there's this title structure she uses. The X will make you Y. And you can see the rule of opposites will make people obsessive view. The cognitive bias will give you cult like fans. The enemy effect will make you magnetic.
[Speaker 1] So she's using very cool content. She's using very curiosity driven language. She's got social proof in here, like pop culture sort of stuff as well. Social hacking, sorry.
[Speaker 1] And we might then turn around and go, right, I'm gonna take all of these things and apply them to my channel. So I ideate a video that looks like this. I've got the X will make you Y title going on down here. I've got some psychological principles in there. I've got some curiosity driven language. I'm using The Rock and Taylor Swift. Who's not gonna click on that? Well, let me tell you something. This video would flop harder than turning it off. I'm turning off the air supply to one of those inflatable tube men you see outside of car garages in America. Because look at my channel. Like I built the thing on clear strategic promises in my titles and thumbnails and like authority back phrasing and clear end results and saying I'm gonna build a system. I did not build my channel on psychological principles to get specific results. I don't know anything about that. I can barely say it. I also don't use celebrities because I don't think you guys care about The Rock or Taylor Swift. And I'm never gonna teach people about the rule of attraction because I don't have a clue what that is. So this lady is blowing up and what's gonna happen on your journey is you're gonna come across all this data and you're gonna ideate from it and you're gonna have big flops because you won't have necessarily established exactly what your viewers want yet or you'll leave what they want and try something new and it'll flop. So the name of the game here really is realizing that just cause it worked for one channel doesn't mean it will definitely work for us. And the only way we're actually gonna be able to discover this is of course, with the, you know, with the annoying graph map thingy I keep showing you where we come up with ideas, we test it, we measure it, we adjust, and then we repeat what works. So only what works is left and grows our channel. So what you wanna do is research patterns, test, keep works and don't just blindly copy unrelated patterns and expect identical results cause it just doesn't work like that. So as I mentioned, ongoing, you're gonna batch three to four videos at once and then you repeat what works. And what we really wanna end up with is like three tried and tested formats. You keep repeating. So that's all you need to do right now. Next, we're gonna move on to planning the content. I'm gonna teach you how to plan and then we're gonna plan this video together.